你还好吗  老爸
How we doing, Pops?
我还剩一周想清楚
You know, like I got a week to figure out
以后的日子我要干什么
the hell I'm gonna do with my days.
三十年了  我唯一的爱好就是抱怨工作
30 years, and my only hobby was bitching about my job.
警察都这样
Ah, that's the cop way.
-你会想清楚的  -嗯
- You'll figure it out. - Yeah.
先生们
Gentlemen.
-鲍勃  -瑞兹
- Bob! - Rizzy!
-老哥们  -鲍勃
- Old man. - Hey, Bob.
你还记得我儿子吗  亚当
You remember my boy, Adam.
脸上都起褶了  不认得这个
With scruff on his face, I don't.
达夫
Hey, Duff.
我们只想过来看看  你一般是怎么办这种活动的
We just wanted to stop by, see how you usually do it.
我觉得我们办这些活动还挺不错的
Yeah, we got these things down pretty good, I think.
我想你应该会需要整个场地  对吧
Figure you don't need the whole place, right?
不不  15人  20人最多了
No, no. 15, 20 max.
那我们把那片区域关闭
Well, we'll get that area closed off,
为你预留  放一些零食
set aside for you, put out some snacks.
不会太复杂
Won't be too complicated.
一般需要一个押金
Usually take a little deposit.
大概两百
200 maybe?
-挺合理的  -对  等等
- Seems fair. - Uh, yeah, yeah, hang on.
等等
Hang on.
爸  我来吧
Dad, I got it.
真的吗
Yeah?
没人该给自己的退休会自掏腰包
You don't pay for your own retirement party.
来吧
Come on.
鲍勃·鲁塞克
Bob Ruzek.
你终于要退休放牧了啊
Finally putting you out to pasture.
总比被人带到谷仓一枪爆头好吧
Well, better than being taken behind the barn and shot, I guess.
那是自然
That's right.
不是说芝加哥警署里
What does it say about the Chicago Police Department
你们提供的咖啡是楼里最好的吗
that you turkeys serve up the best coffee in the building?
其实不怎么样  警长
Nothing good, Sarge.
我看见楼下舞神鲍勃的退休派对传单了
I saw the flyer downstairs about Disco Bob's party.
对  这周末  别有压力
Yeah, this weekend. No obligation.
你疯了吗  我从不去这种活动
Are you nuts? I don't go to those things.
很多年前  当我们还是菜鸟在13分局工作时
Years ago, when we were babies working at the 13th,
你爸来上班的时候
your dad would show up for his shift
一直叨叨着你前一晚的比赛成绩
reciting your stats from your game the night before.
"亚当昨晚三比四
"Adam went three for four last night
一个双杀  还打了两个点"
with a double and two RBIs."
我们应该继续这个传统
Well, we should definitely keep doing that.
亚当昨晚三比四
Adam went three for four last night
吃了一个大号三明治和两瓶啤酒
with a hoagie and two beers.
还有一个腌黄瓜
And a sacrifice pickle.
人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
真棒
Heyo.
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
给你老爸的
Something for your old man.
谢了  老大  你没必要破费
Thanks, boss. You didn't have to do that.
我知道你过去跟他有过节
I know you had your issues with him over the years.
翻译    nemonini   哈里不是波特
三十年的芝加哥警察
30 years of service to the city of Chicago
就是三十年警察  仅此而已
is 30 years of service-- end of story.
翻译    苏葵*4
谢谢
Appreciate it.
校对    苏葵
晚饭你想吃什么
What are you hungry for for dinner?
我们去克莱伯恩街那个店吧
Let's go to that place on Clybourn.
时间轴    Jenny   西查   chance-coco
你管那里叫什么  柏拉图披萨
What do you call it? Platonic Pizza?
柏拉图派
Platonic Pie.
因为你选的词精练多了
Oh, 'cause that's so much snappier.
后期    8T
这是个技能
It's a skillset.
我去一趟我爸家
Swing by my dad's house quick.
总监    苏葵
好
All right.
我就把这个送进去
I'll just run this inside,
然后我们就去接玛凯拉
and then we'll go pick up Makayla.
好吗
Okay?
还是这样吧
Actually, you know what?
不如你进来  看看我爸
Why don't you come in, see the old man?
他肯定开心见到你
He'd be happy to see your face.
来吧
Come on.
-你确定吗  -当然  来吧
- You sure? - Yeah, come on.
-确定确定吗  -确定
- Sure, sure? - Yeah.
你跟他说了那些
Have you told him about...
你让我心碎的时刻吗
All the times you broke my heart?
没有  你没事
No. You're good.
你是保护我不受他的怒火攻击吗
Are you protecting me from his wrath?
不  我只是觉得如果他要被逼做选择
No, I just figured if he was ever forced to make a choice,
他肯定选你不选我
he'd pick you over me.
我就会这么选
I mean, that's the choice I would make.
老爸  希望你穿衣服了
Pops, I hope you're decent.
我带姑娘回来了
Coming in with the girl.
爸
Dad?
Hey, Dad?
爸
Dad?
鲍勃
Bob?
亚当
Adam.
好吧  我打电话给他
All right. I'm gonna call him.
好
Yeah.
电话通了
All right. It's ringing.
这是怎么回事
What the hell is this?
爸
Dad?
亚当来电
-这边还有更多血  -是啊
- More blood down here. - Yeah...
爸
Dad!
这些血还是刚流的  亚当
That blood is fresh, Adam.
你问到消息了吗
You got anything?
算是吧
Uh, sort of.
我问了一个邻居
I spoke to a neighbor.
她说看到两个男人把车停在了屋后
She said she saw two men pull up to the back of the house.
白人  可能是西班牙裔  他们进屋了
White, possibly Hispanic. They entered.
大概二十分钟前离开的
Then they left about 20 minutes ago.
这是个开始  我们上报吧
It's a start. Call it in.
怎么了
What?
只是  金  我爸  你懂的
It's just, Kim, my dad, you know,
他这些年做过很多糟糕的决定
he's made some pretty crappy choices over the years.
我不知道这里发生了什么
I don't know what happened in here,
但也很有可能他是自残
but there's a decent chance it was self-inflicted.
或许吧
Maybe.
但你还是得上报
But you gotta call it in.
5021I
5021 Ida.
请讲  5021I
Go ahead, Ida.
我需要你派取证人员
I need you to roll a crime lab
前往奥兰德北街221号
to 221 North Oleander.
可能是非法闯入  还有绑架
Possible home invasion, possible kidnapping.
收到  取证人员正在前往
Copy that. Crime lab en route.
芝加哥警署
第八季第十集
怎么样啊  你还好吗
What up, dog? You good?
不太好
I've been better.
不太清楚发生了什么
I don't know what happened there, boys,
但反正不会是好事
but it wasn't good, whatever it was.
不管发生了什么  我们都会查清楚
Well, you know, whatever it is, we gonna figure it out.
有我们呢
We got you.
谢了  几位
Appreciate it, fellas.
我跟你说了把那辆车开走
I told you to get that van out of here.
收到  警长
Copy, Sergeant.
大家听我说
All right. Everybody, listen to me.
鲍勃·鲁塞克最不想看到的
The last thing Bob Ruzek needs
就是他的脸出现在晚间新闻上
is his face on the evening news.
大家就是这么出事的
That's how people get hurt.
把巡警弄走
Send patrol away.
我们要以最高机密来查这个案子
We're working this as a 99 Confidential.
只和组织犯罪技术部沟通
Only OCD in the loop.
但这就意味着案子全靠我们自己
But that means this is all on us.
好吗  现在情况怎样
All right? Where are we?
房子里有搏斗的痕迹
Okay. We got a struggle inside the house.
厨房有血迹
There's blood in the kitchen
一直流到后门
which leads to the backdoor.
很明显我父亲是匆匆忙忙走的
Pretty clear my father left in a hurry
而且并非出于他的本意
and it wasn't his idea to do so.
他的车在  电视还开着
I mean, his car is here. The TV was on.
钥匙  钱包  配枪
His keys, his wallet, service revolver,
手机  手机我刚开始查
his phone, which I just started going through.
密码是他的警号
Password was his badge number
因为谁会想到用这个呢
'cause who would've thought of that?
有什么不寻常的东西吗
Okay. Anything jump out?
没有  都是正常的东西
No, it's all just normal stuff.
这里是我在给他发短信说退休派对的事
I mean, here I am texting him about the retirement party.
怎么了
What?
告诉我
Talk to me.
上面说
It says,
你没能履行承诺  结束了
周二  6点13分
Tuesday, 6:13,
"你没能履行承诺  结束了"
"You don't deliver, it's over."
没有显示的号码
It's a restricted number.
知道谁可能会发这样的短信
All right, any idea who might send something like that
给你老爸吗
to your old man?
不知道
No.
技术部说脚印
Tech said that the footprints
和流到后门的血迹
and the blood leading to the back door
是人穿着袜子故意弄的
were made by somebody wearing socks.
如果是看起来的样子的话  有人抓了他
So if this is what it seems, somebody grabbed him.
连穿鞋的机会都没给他
Didn't even give him a chance to put his shoes on.
继续排查这个街区
All right. Keep canvassing this block.
找些监控视频出来
Find some cameras.
收集足够的材料后给车辆发个协查通报
Scrape together enough to get a BOLO out on that car.
-金  -在
- Kim. - Yeah.
我要对鲍勃·鲁塞克的所有案子做全面审查
I want a full scrub of all of Bob Ruzek's cases,
从头到尾
top to bottom.
这种事发生到我们中谁的头上的话
Something like this happened to one of us,
我们首先会想到它和某个案子有关联
the first thing we'd think it's related to a case somehow.
-对  -报仇
- Right. - Revenge,
-有人想要找什么消息  -头儿
- somebody seeking information-- - Boss.
我老爸过去20年都在白袜队下午的赛事中
My pop spent the last 20 years directing traffic
指挥交通呢  从来没有入户调查
at afternoon Sox games, not kicking in doors.
我觉得金不会有什么发现
I mean, I don't think Kim's gonna find anything there.
他仍然是警官
Okay, he's still a police officer.
他做巡警那么多年  去过很多地方
That man spent a lot of time on a lot of streets.
好好查吧
Do the work.
交给我吧
Now, I'm on it.
-找谁啊  -我要见本尼
- Can I help you? - Gonna see Benny.
喂  你不能进里面去
Hey. You can't go back there.
酒吧已关
不  别动
No. Nope.
-别动  -本尼
- Nope. - Benny.
亚当
Adam.
本尼  我们得聊聊
Benny, we need to talk.
大家都出去
Everybody, out.
亚当  你搞什么
Adam, the hell is this?
我不是亚当  本尼
There's no Adam here, Benny.
今晚不是
Not tonight.
我就是个死死盯着你的警察
There's just a cop up your ass.
-我父亲呢  本尼  -什么
- Where's my father, Benny? - What?
我知道你给他发过短信  告知他要履行承诺
I know you texted him, told him to deliver.
-我没有...  -他人呢  本尼
- I didn't-- - Where is he, Benny?
-不是我干的  我发誓  -不不不  他在哪
- That wasn't me; I swear. - No, no, no, where is he?
-我...我不...  -本尼
- I--I don't-- - Benny.
喂  你打伤我老爸了吗
Hey, hey. Did you hurt my dad?
不  不是我
No, no. I did not.
-你打伤我老爸了吗  -不  不是我
- Did you hurt my dad? - No, I did not.
听我说
Listen to me.
你深呼吸一下
Now you just take a breath.
我会一五一十全都告诉你
I will tell you exactly what happened,
而你可不要做什么疯狂的事
and you are not gonna do anything bananas.
行吗
Deal?
告诉我发生了什么事吧
Tell me what happened.
你老爸  我不扯谎  是和我有麻烦
Your pops-- I am not gonna lie--was in trouble with me.
-很严重  -有多严重
- Bad. - How bad?
非常严重
Like real bad.
实际上  你知道  我知道
Truth is, you know it. I know it.
他是我认识的最糟糕的赌徒
He's the worst gambler I ever knew.
给自己挖了个坑  而且越挖越深
Got into a hole and just kept digging deeper
直到我最后不再让他赌了
until I finally cut him off.
本尼  告诉我欠了多少
Benny, just tell me how much.
八万
80 grand.
80 grand?
本尼  这次你怎么能让他欠这么多呢
Benny, how could you let it get that bad this time?
-如果你说了...  -听我说
- I mean, if you said hey, I-- - Listen to me.
我没动你父亲一根毫毛
I did not lay a finger on your father.
原因很简单
And the reason is simple.
他还钱了  全还了
He paid. All of it.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
-用现金  -不
- In cash. - No.
某天晚上他走进来  扔下钱
Walked in one night, dropped it,
就走了  从那之后我就没见过他
walked out, I ain't seen him since.
-是吗  什么时候  -大约一个月前
- Yeah? When's this? - About a month ago.
你需要的话账本上有日期
Date's in the ledger book if you need it.
抱歉  本尼
Sorry, Benny.
怎么  你在跟踪我
What, are you following me?
对  对
Yes. Yes.
听着  你在你爸家看到那条短信时
Look, you were clearly lying to Voight
明显是在骗博伊特
when you saw that text at your dad's house.
我想确定
I wanted to make sure
你没做什么出格的事
you weren't doing something extracurricular,
或出去犯傻  你有吗
just plain ol' stupid. Were you?
有  说得没错
Yeah. That'd be fair to say.
然后呢
And?
原来几周前
And, well, it turns out a few weeks ago,
我爸还了八万块的债
my father paid down an 80 grand debt.
而几小时之前  他在酒吧里
A few hours ago, he couldn't put down
连两百块订金都付不起
a $200 deposit on a bar.
现在他不见了
And now he's gone.
好  好
Okay. Okay.
你知道他怎么弄到八万块的吗
You know how he got the 80 grand?
不知道
No, I don't.
我以为我知道怎么回事
I thought I knew what was going on.
但我不知道
I don't.
我们会查出来的
Hey. We're gonna figure it out.
对
Yeah.
还是那个受限制的号码
It's the same restricted number.
是个视频
It's a video.
-你好  儿子  -天哪
- Hello, son. - Oh, my God.
我没事  我很好
I'm okay. I'm all right.
我只是  我有点麻烦
I just, um-- I'm in a bit of trouble here.
这些家伙  暴君帮
These guys--Los Tiranos--
我不需要告诉你他们是谁
I don't need to tell you who they are.
他们出了点问题
They got a problem.
有个告密者
A snitch.
在他们内部
Someone on the inside
给他们造成了麻烦
that's giving them trouble.
所以他们需要你  我需要你
So they need you-- I need you--
找出这个人是谁
to find out who it is.
然后把名字告诉他们  好吗
And then give them the name, okay?
不然我就彻底没命了  儿子  我就没命了
Or I'm gone for good, son. I'm gone.
我们再联系
We'll be back in touch.
有位芝加哥警察失踪了12小时
We got a Chicago cop missing 12 hours.
告诉我点好消息
Tell me something good.
我们联系组织犯罪技术部了吗
We looped in OCD?
我们发现鲁塞克警官的手机上有捕获追踪装置
We got trap-and-trace on Officer's Ruzek's phone,
但目前还没有任何发现
but so far, nothing.
好  他的警察工作审查有什么新进展
Okay. What's the latest on the scrub of his police work?
我正在查  警长
I'm into it, Sarge.
只是可查的东西不多
It's just not a lot of meat on the bone.
好  警长  这里是暴君帮宣称的地盘
Okay, so, Sarge, this is the claim territory of Los Tiranos,
就是那个抓了鲍勃·鲁塞克的拉美裔黑帮
the Hispanic gang that's holding down Bob Ruzek.
这些家伙是伞形架构的团伙
So these guys are an umbrella gang,
-贩毒帮派  -好
- cartel-connected. - Okay.
他们有数百名底层毒贩
They got hundreds of foot soldiers,
几十个派系  每个派系都有藏匿屋
dozens of cliques, each one is a silo.
得花点时间才能摸清他们的底细
It's gonna take some time to put a face to this.
对  他们占领了下西区
Right, so they occupy the Lower West Side,
下西区
南环和马歇尔广场
the South Loop, Marshall Square,
但中心地带正好在皮尔森
but the heart of it happens right here in Pilsen.
所以我们有理由相信
So we got reason to believe
这些人不是在开玩笑
these guys know what they're talking about.
暴君帮已经逍遥法外很长时间了
I mean, Los Tiranos was running unchecked for a long time,
但近几个月
but the last couple months,
他们受到了一些打击
they've taken some hits.
芝加哥警署让他们吃了些苦头
CPDs punched 'em in the face a few times.
捣毁了他们的几处藏匿屋
Hit a couple of their stash houses
和几个银行账户
and a couple bank accounts.
我们觉得他们内部一定有线人
We're thinking that there has to be an informant on the inside--
告密者
a snitch.
刚刚拿到现场取回的血样
Just got the bloodwork back from the scene.
有些血迹肯定是鲁塞克警官的
So some of the blood definitely belongs to Officer Ruzek.
但好消息是  大部分血迹是其他人的
But the good news is most of it belongs to someone else,
而且我们在DNA联合索引找到了匹配
and we got a hit on CODIS.
这是赫克托·阿尔瓦罗·圣地亚哥
This is Hector Alvaro Santiago,
出生于88年3月30日
date of birth 03/30/88.
他在帮派数据库中
He's in the gang database.
是暴君帮的已知成员
He's a known member of Los Tiranos.
他在皮尔森有住处  南奥尔波特539号
He's got an LKA in Pilsen. 539 South Allport.
干得好  出发
Nice work. Let's move.
芝加哥警署
Chicago PD!
芝加哥警署  举起手来
Chicago PD. Hands up.
-朝我这边走  -什么
- You walk towards me. - What?
举起手  朝我这边走
Hands in the air. Step towards me.
-不  -放开他
- No! - Get away from him.
起来
Get up.
-不不不  -鲍勃·鲁塞克在哪里
- No, no, no, no, no, no. - Where is Bob Ruzek?
-谁  -你知道是谁  鲍勃·鲁塞克
- Who? - You know who--Bob Ruzek.
我不知道他是谁
I don't know who that is.
这房子里还有谁
Who else is in this house?
鲍勃·鲁塞克在哪里
Hey. Where's Bob Ruzek?
听我说  鲍勃·鲁塞克在哪里
I need you to hear me. Where is Bob Ruzek?
告诉我他在哪里
Tell me where he is.
鲍勃·鲁塞克警官
Officer Bob Ruzek.
他家里全是你的血
Your blood's all over his house.
我们要知道原因  醒醒
We need to know why. Hey!
房子是空的  他不在这里
House is empty. He's not here.
救救他
Help him!
别死在我面前
Don't you die on me.
我爸呢
Where's my dad?
赫克托
Hector!
-我父亲呢  -亚当
- Where's my father? - Adam.
不
No!
5021E
5021 Eddie.
让取证室的人和救护车来南奥尔波特539号
Roll a crime lab and ambo to 539 South Allport.
艾琳娜  你和赫克托在一起一年了
Okay, Elena, you and Hector were together for a year.
这是很长时间了  好吗
That's a very long time, okay?
很久了
That's a long time.
但我需要你想想  好好回忆
But I need you to remember. I need you to think.
你记得赫克托用过鲍勃·鲁塞克这个名字吗
Do you ever remember Hector using the name Bob Ruzek?
你一直在说这个名字
You keep saying that name.
那是谁
Who is that?
好吧  那告诉我
All right. Tell me this.
赫克托受伤前你最后一次见他是什么时候
When's the last time you saw Hector before he got injured?
昨天早上
Yesterday morning.
就是普通的一天
It was a regular day.
在我去诊所的路上送了他
Dropped him on my way to the clinic.
诊所
The clinic?
阿尔登家庭健康诊所  我是个护士
Arden Family Health. I'm a nurse.
下班后回家  我发现他在流血
Got home from work, and I found him bleeding.
好吧  你是护士
Okay. You're a nurse.
但你不带他去医院吗
And you didn't bring him to the hospital?
帮我理解下
Help me understand that.
他说自己能不能活就看我的了
He told me it was going to be up to me to save his life or not.
我知道他肯定会流血而死
I knew he was going to bleed out eventually.
就求他去医院
Begged him to go to the hospital.
-他不肯去  -艾琳娜
- He wouldn't go. - Elena.
你是个护士  你的男友大出血
You're a nurse. Your man's bleeding out,
他还不愿意去医院
and he won't go to the hospital.
你不觉得这很奇怪吗
That didn't strike you as odd?
这都没引起你的怀疑吗
It didn't bring up any questions in your mind?
你知道他是混黑帮的吗
Did you know that he was in a gang?
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yes.
赫克托是混黑帮的
Hector was in a gang.
所以他不愿意去医院
That's why he didn't want to go to the hospital.
因为他知道如果去急诊室
Because he knew that if he showed up at an ER
还大出血  以他这样的身份
bleeding out, someone like him was gonna start
肯定会被问很多他不愿回答的问题
getting asked questions that he didn't wanna answer.
-你撒谎  -不  撒谎的是他
- You lie. - No, he lied.
你对这个男人有任何了解吗
Did you know anything about the man?
有空吗
Can I get a sec?
-你问过他任何问题吗  -亚当
- Did you ask any questions at all? - Adam.
博伊特想做全面审查是正确的
Voight was right to do the scrub.
我追踪了你爸所有想登录的
I tracked everything that your dad tried to access
电脑数据库  所有按键
in the computer database, every keystroke.
有发现
Something there.
是坏消息
Something bad.
三天前  在他下班后
Three days ago, at the end of his shift,
你爸登录进了黑帮数据库
your dad logged in to the gang database
并查看了记录在案的暴君帮成员列表
and accessed the list of documented members of Los Tiranos.
你爸不跟黑帮合作
Your dad doesn't work with gangs.
他也不在重案组
He doesn't work major crimes.
他没有理由去查看那些信息
There's no reason that he would need that information.
-对  -但还不止如此
- Right. - But it doesn't end there.
因为他拿到了名字后
Because once he has the names,
他就利用那些名字去搜查
he uses them to pull the field reports
最近的反黑行动外勤报告
for the recent operations targeting the gang.
然后呢
And?
有一份报告提到了一个线人
And one of those reports mentions a CI,
代号叫做梅林
goes by the codename Merlin.
好吧  但他不知道这个梅林是谁  对吧
All right, but he doesn't know this Merlin, right?
-他在视频里说  -亚当
- He said in the video-- - Adam.
他不知道他是谁
He doesn't know who he is,
但不是因为他没去找
but it's not for lack of trying.
他想找到梅林的真名
He tried to get Merlin's real name.
但他只是
But he's just...
他是个巡警  他没有足够高的安全权限
He's a patrol cop, and he doesn't have security clearance.
好  好吧
All right. All right.
我去看一眼这个
I'm just gonna take a look at this.
我想重溯他的所有步骤
I wanna retrace his steps again.
亚当
Adam.
时间到了  儿子
Time's up, son.
我们得行动了
We gotta do this.
或不干
Or not.
-你有空吗  -对
- You have a minute? - Yeah.
他们又发来一个视频
They sent a second video.
在里面放了个钟
They put a clock on it.
他们想要那个给他们找麻烦的告密者名字
They want the name of the snitch that's giving them trouble,
他们向明天中午就知道
and they want it by noon tomorrow.
那我们就熬夜查案
So we work all night.
我们会尽全力
We'll do whatever we gotta do--
老大  老大  还有其他消息
Boss, boss, there's more.
我父亲一直在帮这个黑帮办事
My father's been doing favors for this gang--
至少他在尝试
at least he's been trying.
我刚复制了他的步骤
I just retraced his steps.
他用逮捕数据库去找一个告密者
He used the arrest database to find his way to the snitch,
代号梅林  而且他试图
codename Merlin, and then he tried
找出告密者的真名
to find the snitch's real name.
如果真是如此
Um, if that's true...
他就完全背叛了警局  我知道
It's a complete betrayal of the badge, I know.
但是  只是因为他试了  不意味着他成功了
But, uh, just because he tried doesn't mean he succeeded.
舞神鲍勃的日常罢了
Story of Disco Bob's life.
不  他觉得你能做到他不能做的
No, he thinks you can do what he couldn't--
找出梅林是谁
figure out who this Merlin is.
他也没错
Well, he's not wrong.
我们的安全等级比巡警高
I mean, we have higher clearance than Patrol.
我已经绕过了他碰的壁
I already got past the wall that he ran into.
梅林是检察官特别小组的线人
Merlin works for a DA task force
调查贩毒集团  其中包括暴君帮
that investigates cartels including Los Tiranos.
这个线人  他参与了三十多起案件
I mean, this CI, he's indexed in over 30 cases.
他很擅长自己的工作  无论这人是谁
He is very good at what he does, whoever he is.
好吧  那么
Okay, so...
假如你是我
Say you're me, right?
接下去怎么做
What happens next?
我们找出梅林的真名  去做交易
We find Merlin's real name. We make the trade.
那我们去做交易
So we make the trade.
你爸活着出来
Your old man walks out alive.
那  那算是希望  对吧
I mean, that's-- that's the hope, right?
但梅林就死了
But Merlin's dead.
这是肯定的
That's for sure.
这可是一命换一命
We're talking about trading one life for another.
但另一个人的命是梅林  黑帮成员
But one life is Merlin, who's a gang member.
他是个叛徒
He's a rat.
老大  如果过着清白的生活不会落到
Boss, you don't get to the position that Merlin's in
梅林现在的位置
by living some clean life.
亚当
Adam.
如果过着清白的生活也不会落到
You don't get to the position your father's in
你爸现在的位置
by leading a clean life.
是吧
Do you?
是的  长官
No, sir.
但他是我父亲
But he's my father.
无论何时我都愿意为你做这样的交易
I would make the same trade for you every time.
我去找特别小组
I'm gonna go to the task force.
你别管这部分
You stay out of this part.
-我要带海莉去  -好
- I'm taking Hailey. - All right.
亚当  听我说
Adam, listen to me.
我会拿到那个名字
I'm gonna get that name
因为这是我们找到你父亲的最佳机会
because it's our best chance to find your father
靠我们自己找到  在截止日期前
on our own before the deadline
还不做交易
without making that trade.
你明白吗
You understand?
我们不干一命换一命的买卖
We're not in the business of signing execution papers.
这些混蛋想要梅林的名字
So these pricks want Merlin's name.
对  如果我们不给他们  他们肯定会杀了他
Yeah, if we don't give it to 'em, they're gonna kill him--
芝加哥警察  明天动手
the Chicago cop--tomorrow.
现在麻烦大了
Well, we got some real problems here.
那是谁
Who's that?
那是梅林
That's Merlin.
什么
What?
她在暴君帮顺风顺水  但其实是我们的人
Now she climbs the Tiranos ladder, but she works for us.
她很宝贵
She's a gold mine.
一旦被杀  两年的辛劳全都白费
She gets killed, that's two years of work up in smoke.
这是算上从这直到圣路易斯的贩毒黑帮
We're talking cartel-connected gangs from here to St. Louis.
听着  我们也跟你们一样不希望发生那些
Look--we don't want that any more than you do.
但现在一名警察的生命有危险
But a cop's life's on the line here,
我们希望你们能折中配合我们一下
and we're hoping that you can meet us in the middle.
不用给我们梅林的名字
How about instead of Merlin's name,
给我们一个其他名字
you give us someone else's?
谁
Who?
想要梅林性命的人
The person who wants Merlin dead.
给我们那个名字
Give us that name.
我们利用那个信息去找鲍勃·鲁塞克
Then we'll use that information to find Bob Ruzek.
我们抓他回来  保护你们的线人
We'll bring him in and protect your source.
梅林的工作现在让一个人的生活如同地狱
Merlin's work has made one man's life a living hell.
他叫卢卡斯·布雷拉
His name is Lucas Barela.
出生日期71年11月8日
Date of birth: 11/08/71.
布雷拉是帮派的洗钱人
Barela's the juice man of the gang.
他洗钱的方法是
His arm of the business is to launder money
给走投无路的人现金贷款
by issuing cash loans to desperate people
收取大额利息
at high interest rates.
比如爱赌博的警察
Like cops with gambling issues.
对  比如那种
Yeah. Like that.
好  记住  卢卡斯·布雷拉也是个走投无路的人
Okay, remember, Lucas Barela is also a desperate man.
他也命悬一线
His life's at stake here too.
对  被警察突袭的藏钱屋是布雷拉的
Yeah, so it was Barela's money houses that were hit by the cops,
布雷拉的银行账户也被封了
Barela's bank accounts that were frozen.
这要感谢梅林
We can thank Merlin for that.
所以特别小组在监听他们
So the task force has wiretaps up,
我们知道布雷拉的老大给了他最后一次机会
and we know that Barela's bosses have given him one more chance
让他整顿好自己的内务  否则他就会死
to get his house in order, or he's dead.
警长  为了审查调取的大陪审团文本记录
Sarge, the grand jury transcripts you had me pull for the scrub.
-死的那个人  赫克托·圣地亚哥  -嗯
- The guy who died, Hector Santiago... - Right.
他的表亲就是布雷拉  也是他的打手  他们很铁
His cousin is Barela. Also, his muscle. They were tight.
等等
Hold on.
圣地亚哥的女友告诉我
Santiago's girlfriend told me
她以前去上班是会把他送到一个仓库
she used to drop him off at some warehouse for work
在她去阿尔登家庭健康诊所的路上
on her way to, uh, Arden Family Health.
阿尔登家庭健康诊所
Arden Family Health.
阿尔登家庭健康诊所在皮尔森的毕夏普街和21街
Arden Family Health is on Bishop and 21st in Pilsen.
不如我们查查在诊所和
So why don't we run all the warehouses
圣地亚哥家之间所有的仓库
between the clinic and Santiago's house?
有了  19街和阿伯丁路
Yeah. 19th and Aberdeen.
三年前关闭
Closed three years ago.
布雷拉清算了
Barela liquidated.
库克县
布雷拉夫妇财产  19街和阿伯丁路
找到了  仓库倒闭前属于布雷拉的父母
Got it. Barela's parents owned it before it went under.
名字还写在契约上
The name's still on the deed.
那好家伙什  我们走
Strap up. Go hit it.
好  库珀  瞄准上面
All right, Coop, get 'em high.
瞄准上面
Get 'em high.
在那边
Right there.
到了
There you go.
我在那掩护你  你在这掩护我
I got you there. You got me here.
收到
Copy.
清算
我们进去了
We're in.
爸
Dad?
他还活着  叫救护车  停在一个街区外
I found him alive. Roll an ambo. Park it a block away.
不知道楼里还有几个嫌犯
Unknown number of offenders in the building.
收到
Copy that.
爸
Dad?
来  给你暖和暖和
Here. Let's get you warm.
披好了  给你暖和暖和
Here you go. Let's get you warm.
你没事了
You're all right.
我就知道  我就知道你会来
I knew it. I knew you'd come.
小声点
Keep your voice down.
-你没事了  -好  好的
- You're all right. - Yeah. All right.
安静点
Just be quiet.
有多少人  这里有多少人
How many are there? How many are there?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
是布雷拉吗  是他把你绑来的吗
Is it Barela--is that the one that did this to you?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
他们没用名字
They didn't use names.
-你能走吗  -嗯  我想可以
- You okay to move? - Yeah, I think so.
起来  我们回家
Get up. Let's go home.
好
Okay.
我扶住你了
I got you.
往前走  我扶住你了
Go ahead. I got you.
-发现有人  在下层  -收到
- I got movement, lower level. - Copy.
卢卡斯·布雷拉  别动
Lucas Barela, don't move!
他往西穿过大楼跑了  守住出口
He's running west through the building--cover those exits.
收到  我们绕过去
Copy. We're coming around!
停下
Stop!
好  好  跟我一起行动
All right, all right. Move with me.
注意着点  注意着点
Let's go wide. Go wide.
这边有人
We got motion right here.
芝加哥警署  布雷拉  站住
Chicago PD! Barela, stop!
-让开  -赶紧  走开
- Out of the way! - Come on, move.
-让开  -停车
- Out of the way! - Stop!
-快  继续  -从车里出来
- Come on, keep it moving. - Get out of the car.
离开这里  让开
Get out of here. Get out the way!
走开  帮她
Move. Help her!
帮她  帮她
Help her! Help her!
布雷拉开车平民的车往19街开了
Barela going down 19th in a civilian vehicle!
-乔伊  -亚当
- Hey, Joy. - Adam, hey.
他怎么样
How's he doing?
断了两根肋骨  有些低温症
Two broken ribs, some hypothermia.
他经历了折磨  但他会没事的
He went through hell, but he'll be fine.
好  那就好
All right. That's good.
他能穿些真正的衣服吗
He okay to put on some real clothes?
很快了  他很快就能出院了
Mm, close enough. He'll be out of here soon.
谢谢  乔伊
Thank you, Joy.
警官
Officer.
爸
Pa.
你来了
Ah, there he is.
谢了  儿子
Thanks, son.
好了  老爸
All right, Pops.
该说实话了
Truth time.
你得告诉我们一切  让我们找到卢卡斯·布雷拉
You gotta tell me everything so we can find Lucas Barela.
绑架我的那个人吗
Oh, the guy who took me?
对
Yeah.
卢  卢卡斯  什么
Lu--Lucas? Wh--
-你说什么  布雷拉  -别装了
- What'd you say? Barela? - Stop what you're doing.
你很清楚他是谁
You know exactly who he is.
你25年前逮捕了他
You arrested him 25 years ago.
他靠提供信息获得减刑
He got a reduced sentence in exchange for information.
他为你工作
He worked for you.
所以你很清楚卢卡斯·布雷拉是谁  爸
So you know exactly who Lucas Barela is, Dad.
告诉我
Talk to me.
你很厉害  儿子
You're good, kid.
那时候  我是说了算的人
Back then, I was the guy in charge.
布雷拉只是个街头叛徒
Barela was a street rat.
这么多年后  事情改变了
And over the years, you know, things changed.
我还在原来的位置
I stayed right where I was,
但布雷拉  他爬到了顶端
but Barela, he climbed to the top.
你就是这样付清和本尼的欠账
And that's how paid off your debt with Benny.
你去找布雷拉借钱了  对吧
You went to Barela, right?
对
Yeah.
-每周十成利息  -天呐
- 10% a week. - Oh, my God.
你到底有什么毛病
What the hell is wrong with you?
你这一百万年也还不清了
You couldn't pay that off in a million years.
-你在想什么  -我知道
- What are you thinking? - I know.
他也知道  他贷款给我的时候就知道
He knew--he knew when he gave me the loan.
他在我还不上钱时就知道
He knew when I couldn't pay him back,
他抓住我的把柄了
he had me over a barrel.
他抓住了一个警察的把柄
He had a cop over a barrel.
这价值可大了
That's worth more than--
比任何钱都多
more than any money.
所以那时候他开始
So that's when he, uh--
他命令我
he demanded that I, um,
找出告密者的名字
find out the name of the snitch.
-而我  -什么也没找到  我知道
- And I-- - Came up short. I know.
所以时间到了
So time was up.
然后布雷拉和他的手下
And, uh, Barela and his guy...
-赫克托·圣地亚哥  -对
- Hector Santiago. - Yeah.
他们来了我家
They came to the house.
我拼命抵抗
I fought like hell.
我大概还伤了那个圣地亚哥挺重
I probably hurt that Santiago pretty bad too,
但我  没拿到我的枪
but I--I couldn't get to my piece.
然后
And...
布雷拉用枪抵着我的头
Barela put a gun to my head.
之后
Then--
然后就  我就不行了  我
and then that was-- that was it for me. I...
他准备好了  但我
He was ready, and I...
怎么了  爸
And what, Dad?
我没准备好
I wasn't.
我崩溃了
And I broke.
我做了自己能想到的唯一一件事
I did the only thing I could think of
为了救自己的命  我出卖了自己的儿子
to save my life-- I sold out my own son.
我告诉他你也是个警察  一个真正的警察
I told him that you were a cop, that you were a real cop,
你比我强多了
that you were a better cop than I ever was,
你可以找到告密者的名字
and that you could find the name of that snitch.
我就该吃那颗子弹的
I should've just taken the bullet.
我得找到布雷拉
I need to find Barela.
马上
Now.
不
No.
怎么了  爸  为什么不
What, Dad? What? No.
那男人差点杀了你
The man almost killed you.
你到底在说什么疯话
What the hell are you talking about?
-你得放他走  -我不会放他走的
- You gotta let him walk. - I'm not letting him walk.
你为什么要说这种事
Why--why would you even say that, man?
亚当
Adam,
我已经向他借钱好多年了
I've been borrowing money from him for years--
毒资
drug money.
我还试着拿到线人的名字
And then trying to get the name of the informant?
你要是抓了布雷拉  这一切都会抖出来
You bring Barela in, that all comes out.
那我就完了
That's the end of me.
他们会起诉我  我的养老金也没戏了
They'll bring charges. That'll be the end of my pension.
我们的名字就毁了
Our name will be destroyed.
我们的名字
Our name.
他怎么样了
How is he?
嗯  他会没事的
Yeah. He'll be fine.
没事  门开着吧
It's all right. Leave it open.
警长
Sarge, um,
如果我们找到布雷拉  把他抓回来
you know, if we find Barela and we bring him in,
从中能获得什么好处吗
what would really be gained by that?
你这是认真的问题吗
Is that a real question?
这是
It's just...
这些不干净的事都会被抖出来  太难看了
All this crap comes out, it's ugly.
我父亲的职业  他的养老金
My father's career, his pension.
亚当
Adam.
你不能再包庇他了
You gotta stop covering for him.
你得开始照顾你自己了
You gotta start taking care of you.
我是的
I am.
鲁塞克这名字在警局就毁了
The name Ruzek's gonna stain this department,
在我爸离职后我还得背负这个污名好多年
and I gotta lug that around long after my dad is gone.
所有重要的人
All the people that matter,
他们都知道你是谁
they know who you are.
我只是问问
I'm asking.
答案是不行
The answer's no.
我们之前跟你老爸
We've been down this road before
来过这么一出了  不是吗
with your old man, haven't we?
-做了必要之事  -对  我知道
- Done things we had to do. - Yeah, I know.
结果他就这么回报我们吗
And this is how he repays the favor?
又新找了个毒贩子
Gets in bed with a new drug dealer.
你想让我睁一只眼闭一只眼吗
Now you want me to just walk away?
我们努力过了  然后往前看吗
We gave it a shot? We're moving on?
奥林斯基说你和我爸有过过节
Olinsky told me my dad and you had beef.
他就是个下三滥警察
He was a dog cop!
你以为我会因为跟你老爸二十年前的过节
You think I'm not hearing you because of some beef
而不听你现在说的话吗
I had with your old man 20 years ago?
不是
No.
我告诉你
Let me tell you something.
你这么对一个警察
You do this to a cop--
拿枪抵着他的头  把他从家里绑架走
put a gun to his head, pull him from his home--
这不是对舞神鲍勃一个人做的
you're not doing that to Disco Bob;
这是对整个芝加哥警署做的
you're doing it to the Chicago Police.
你懂吗
You understand?
我们  我们会找到这个卢卡斯·布雷拉
And we--we're gonna find Lucas Barela.
你参不参与随便
You can participate or not.
我会密切关注你的选择的
And I will be watching to see what you choose.
好  线人那里有什么线索
All right. What did we hear from our CIs?
他们嘴都很紧  警长
Buttoned up pretty tight, Sarge.
那就是没进展
So we're nowhere.
好吧  布雷拉偷的车呢
Okay. The vehicle Barela stole?
巡警找到了  被烧毁了
Patrol found it. Torched.
好吧  安全屋  藏匿点
Right. Safehouses, stash houses.
布雷拉在逃命  他肯定在某个地方
Barela's on the run. He's gotta be somewhere.
我们查了所有信息
We've gone through every inch of intel.
-那就是没进展  -也不是  警长
- So we're nowhere. - Maybe not, Sarge.
审查里我发现的最后一个
This is the last piece from the scrub I did
-鲍勃·鲁塞克的活动  -好
- on Bob Ruzek's activity. - Okay.
这是他巡逻车里芯片的数据
This is the data from the chip from his squad car.
他巡逻车的所有停车点
Now every single one of his patrol stops
都是他工作时的出勤点
can be justified as an on-duty call--
所有都合得上  除了一处
all except for this one.
南梅街2451号  在皮尔森
2451 South May. It's in Pilsen.
-暴君帮的大本营  -没错
- In the heart of Los Tiranos. - Exactly.
鲍勃·鲁塞克在那里停了五次
Bob Ruzek stopped there five times.
从没上报  都是私下自己去的
Never called it in. Always off the books.
等等  南梅街2451号
Hold on, you guys. 2451 South May.
布雷拉偷的平民的车被监控拍到了
We've got Barela in that stolen civilian car on a traffic cam,
就在朝那个方向去的一个街区外
and he was a block away from there headed in that direction.
我们走
Let's move.
这些年我们钻了空子的案子多多少
The cases we bent the rules on over the years.
放走的恶棍多多少
The crooks we sent into the wind
就因为把他们抓起来比放走更麻烦
because bringing 'em in was more trouble than it was worth,
但这次  我们就像狗咬骨头一样不松口
but this one, we cling to like a dog on a bone.
从今往后鲁塞克这名字就要成笑话了
The name Ruzek's gonna be a joke from here on out.
我爸确实是个混球  但他说对了一件事
My dad's a jackass, but he's right about one thing.
大家都能好过些  如果卢卡斯·布雷拉就...
Everybody'd be better off if Lucas Barela just...
消失不见
went away.
我们还剩四分钟
We're four minutes out.
悄悄靠近房子  但别行动  等我们来
Move on the house but quiet till we're all there.
好的  我们走
All right. Here we go.
到达现场
On scene.
-我去后面  -等等
- I'll take the back. - Wait.
进屋去
Hey. Back inside.
赶紧回屋
Get back inside now.
亚当
Adam!
你干了什么
What did you do?
5021I
5021 Ida.
警察开枪  一名嫌犯身亡
Shots fired by the police. One offender down.
让取证组过来
Roll the crime lab to our location.
收到
Copy.
副局长和事件响应小组正赶来
Street Deputy and IRT are on their way
展开调查
to open the investigation.
好的  行
All right. Good.
你想谈谈经过吗
You wanna talk it through?
好  没问题
Yeah, sure.
我靠近布雷拉
Went to apprehend Barela.
他伸手拔枪  所以我开枪击毙了他
He reached for his piece, so I put him down.
开了三枪  中了三枪
Shot three times, hit him three times.
两次在后背上
Twice in the back.
这枪开的没问题  老大
It was a good shoot, boss.
事件响应小组和民警问责办公室想找我谈话
IRT and COPA want to talk to me
问问你的心理状况
about your state of mind.
我知道我没看到枪击
I know I didn't see the shooting,
但他们还想听听我的说法
but they want my version.
你确实没看到
Well, you didn't see it.
那还有什么可说的
So what is there to say?
没错
Right.
-这枪开的没问题  -希望如此
- It was a good shoot. - I hope so.
你这是什么意思
Yeah. What does that mean?
意味着我担心你  好吗
It means that I'm worried about you, okay?
我担心
I'm worried.
我最近看着你
I have seen you going
经历了一些烦心事  现在又来这个
through some stuff lately, and now this--
金  别遮遮掩掩的了
Kim, stop dancing around with me.
你有什么想说的直说吧
Say to me what you're really thinking.
说吧
Say it.
他们找到了枪击视频
They got a video of the shoot.
监控录像  隔壁家
Security camera, house next door.
放吧
Play it.
他在对你说什么
What's he saying to you?
他说他知道我是谁
He told me he knew who I was.
说我不会逮捕他
I wouldn't bring him in
因为我父亲已经保证他能走人了
because my father already promised to let him go,
否则他会毁了我爸的职业生涯
and he'd ruin my father's career.
说我跟我爸一样是个狗腿
And that I was a little bitch like my old man.
我说他错了
I told him he was wrong.
他去拔枪
He reached for his gun.
他行动很快  第一枪把他打得转了身
He was moving fast, and the first shot spun him around.
第二和第三枪就击中了他的背
Second and third shots went through his back.
没问题
Good shoot.
事情就和你说的一模一样
That went down exactly like you said,
和你向事件响应小组报告的一模一样
exactly as you reported to IRT.
-干得好  鲁塞克  -谢谢
- That's good work, Ruzek. - Thanks.
-这枪开的没问题  -谢谢
- Nice shoot. - Thanks.
亚当  他还好吗
Hey, Adam. How is he?
嗯  他会没事的  警长
Oh, yeah. He's gonna be fine, Sarge.
他昨天就出院了  所以
He got out of the hospital yesterday, so.
-谢谢关心  警长  -客气
- Thanks for asking, Sarge. - Yeah.
你知道那些你说的
Hey, you know that stuff you said
关于我爸来上班时会说
about my old man coming into shift talking
我在小小联盟的棒球赛吗
about my little league games?
怎么了
Yeah?
全是胡扯
Total BS.
什么
What?
对  他瞎编的
Yeah. He made it up.
这是他爱玩的把戏
That was his shtick.
他当不了真的警察
Couldn't be the real police.
不能做早上第一个来上班的人
Couldn't be the first guy through the door
因为他很顾家
because he was a family man.
就算影响他的事业  他也要回家吃饭
Even if it hurt his career, he had to be home for dinner
不能让我玩游戏
and in the stands for my games.
全是他编的
He made it all up.
他只是在酒吧赌博
He was at the bar making bad bets.
我就知道你击球没那么厉害
I knew you weren't that good a hitter.
-谢了  警长  -不用
- Thanks, Sarge. - Yep.
去跟副警察警司汇报吗
Taking that over to the Deputy Supe?
对  你懂的  这种案子必须汇报
Yeah, you know. Case like this, I gotta.
嗯
Yeah.
只打算说真相
All it says is the truth.
鲁塞科警官背绑架了
Officer Ruzek was abducted
因为嫌犯误认为
because the offender was under the mistaken belief
他知道线人的身份
he knew the identity of a CI.
除此之外的事
Anything else,
都随着卢卡斯·布雷拉的死埋葬了
that'll die with Lucas Barela.
老大
Boss.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
这是我今天听到最好的消息了
That's the best news I've had all day.
你肯定很骄傲  亚当
You must be damn proud, Adam.
有这么个好传承
Hell of a legacy to carry on.
是啊
Sure is.
谢了  达夫
Thanks, Duff.
我们得把话说清楚
We need to clear the air.
好
All right.
-亚当  -当你向我跑来
- Adam-- - When you ran up on me
在我枪击布雷拉后
after I shot Barela,
你本可以问我是否没事
you could've asked me if I was okay,
问我有没有受伤  但你没有问
if I was hurt-- that's not what you did.
-亚当  听着  -你说"你干了什么"
- Adam, listen. - You said, "What did you do?"
对  是的
Yeah, I did.
"你干了什么"
"What did you do?"
金
Kim,
我爱上你的原因之一是因为
one of the many reasons that I fell in love with you
我感觉你相信我
is that I felt like you believed in me.
就像我信任你一样
Like you believed in me
这辈子没人像你这么信任我
in a way that nobody in my entire life has.
我之前是
I did.
-连我自己都不行  -现在也还是
- Even me. - I do.
我不太确定
I'm not so sure.
你得理解我当时那么说是有道理的
You have to see how what I said made sense in the moment.
你得理解
You have to see that.
我不理解
I don't.
在我们经历的这么多事之后
After everything that you and I have been through,
应该存在一种
there just should have been something that...
能把你从怀疑边缘拉回来的信任
Held you back from the edge of assumption.
一个类似于护栏一样
Some sort of guardrail
不让你翻过怀疑这道坎的信任
that kept you from going over that ledge.
如果情况反过来
I mean, if this situation is reversed--
我是你  你是我
I'm you; you're me--
我跑向你
and I run up on you.
你拿着枪站在布雷拉尸体旁
You're standing over Barela holding the gun.
就算我有点怀疑  没事  我也不会跨过去
If I got close to the ledge, fine--I wouldn't go over.
永远不会
Not ever.
我只是
I just...
因为我知道你的为人
'Cause I know your heart.
我知道你永远也不可能
And I know that there's not a world in which
冷血地杀死一个人
you'd kill a man in cold blood,
你不会在他逃跑的时候从背后开枪
that you'd shoot him in the back as he's running away.
为了什么  复仇吗  保护家族名声吗
For what--revenge? For your family name?
拜托
Come on.
但你当时就是这个意思
That's what you meant
当你说"你干了什么"时
when you said, "What did you do?"
在那一刻
And in that moment,
我原以为你也知道我的为人
I'd have thought you'd know my heart.
你应该知道
You're supposed to know.
我知道你的为人  我知道
I do know your heart. I do.
我很抱歉
And I am sorry.
-就...  -我
- Just-- - I--
谢谢你过来看我
Thanks for stopping by.